welcome to the data engineering Nano degree program. I'm
Sam and I'm a product Lee, that udacity.
I worked with a great team of industry experts and
curriculum designers to put this program together, and I'm
very excited to have you join us. So why
Data engineering? Dave Engineering plays a vital role in
storing, organizing and making use of data. The
speed and volume of information we generate every day is
incredible. Every time you open your phone, click
an app or make a purchase, you're creating data
. Many of the products we use on a daily
basis are powered by this data. And companies across
industries are scrambling to reinvent themselves in order to use
data to better serve their customers, build better products
and even make the world a better place. Data
engineers are crucial to this effort. The pipelines they
build databases they design are the foundation that all other
analytics, data science and artificial intelligence efforts are built
on. Without this important work, data simply sits
in a data center and takes up space. Having
strong data engineers is one of the first and most
important steps in the digital transformation process. When working
with big data. There are dozens of tools to
choose from, and it can get confusing fast.
This program will help you understand the big data ecosystem
and build your fluency in a modern set of tools
. The curriculum was designed with input from several expert
data engineers from some of the most advanced data driven
companies in the world, and each of the instructors
has extensive experience in this field. As a result
, the skills you learn are directly applicable. Toe
what data engineers do on the job. During the
program, you'll learn to model data, build production
, ready data warehouses and data lakes, process massive
amounts of data using modern tools and automate data pipelines
. Along the way, you'll build a set of
projects with guidance from mentors. These projects are designed
to imitate what you do on the job as it
it ends here, and every project you submit gets
reviewed, and our project viewers will provide personalized feedback
on how you can improve your work. These projects
will serve as a portfolio you can use to demonstrate
your skills. After completing the program, you'll be
prepared to land a job as a data engineer or
bring these crucial skills to your current role. We're
excited and honored that you're taking this step in your
journey with us.